IL Cafe we have you
covered hello and welcome to Il Cafe
today we're going to talk aboutme
insurance and the context to that is
this one India has 63 million msmes
spread across it and they've been
contributing uh nearly 40% of overall
exports in India now the penetration
rate of General insurance for non-life
insurance in India was 9% in the fiscal
year of 2019 which increased from
0.6% in 2009 so that's the background
and growth that we talking about so
clearly I mean as is evident this is
quite an uphill task for insurers like
icso Lombard um to close the gap that
exists and also engage with smmes very
very effectively so yes that is what
we're going to be doing on I Cafe today
welcome to the show this is Shel and the
person that I have joining us on the
show to help us understand the space a
bit better is Fe Ed and he is an
insurance professional with over two
decades of experience behind him he's
also currently the vice president agency
at ICS y lbad so who better than him to
tell us a little bit more about this and
he also describes by the way himself as
a distribution evangelist through
insurance brokers and advisers and is
working towards realizing the potential
of retail andm so thank you so much aair
for joining us on is Cafe and welcome to
the show how are you thank you for
giving me an opportunity to be a part of
this discussion thanks thanks a lot the
first question has to do with the
efforts that the government has
increased towards promoting technology
upgradation Financial liquidity Market
linkages skill upgradation all of these
which are typically challenges for msmes
and these have been really working
wonders so does that really mean that
the coming year is going to see exciting
times ahead of us because I keep
wondering why insurance doesn't really
get the same level of attention and what
can be done to spread the word f yes
certainly I think the very beautiful
question that we have really coin and
asked me so I'll tell you if you look at
the current situation the unfortunate
part is that not not many smmes are
aware of the business exposure that they
carry in terms of their risk when they
are you know doing in a particular
industry and uh and hence the insurance
becomes a last priority for them to be a
part of their overall uh business
discussions right and that is the only
reason why they exposed to such risk
which probably become a financial issue
at the end of the day for them few
things which comes to my mind apart from
the government intervention I'm sure
government is doing their part but yes
now the and msme trade ass associations
they also play a very very vital and
pivotal role when you start discussing
about their own members well-being their
own wellbeing in terms of the exposures
that's something which is important for
them to do banks now have again started
doing it very aggressively and I'm sure
Banks has a larger penetration which
will ultimately help all of us in
reaching the last mile of smmes thirdly
uh you rightly mention about the
government initiatives yes the
government are taking initiative live
example that I can give you at at this
point in time the Maharashtra
government's initiative about uring all
the you know shop establishments in
Maharaj is a draft that they have rolled
out right that is a very beautiful way
forward for the governments to intervene
and similar kind of a setup has been
done by Kerala government also when
they're giving a subsidy to buy our
insurance policy for thees and mm
registered there so that is a kind of
movement that has really triggered up in
the in the past couple of months and I'm
sure uh see India is a hub of larger
smes and it will go a long way insuring
them right and I like the positive uh
note that you have spun over here for us
and yet you know theem sector we noticed
right was quite severely affected it due
to the liquidity crunch that happened
when the pandemic really hit us and just
to give a context to our viewers that
sector is estimated to be around 42
million plus registered and unregistered
companies that drive about 95% of the
Total Industrial units in India so
that's the size that we're looking at
and if anything covid-19 has taught us
the the need to be prepared for the
unexpected that I think is our biggest
takeaway uh in addition to our focus on
our health uh but in general in
recognition of the sector's contribution
to the economy I would imagine should be
focusing on insurance so what are the
benefits that will ACR to smmes if they
do consider insurance if you look at the
Domain the small and medium Enterprises
are actually exposed to a lot of
potential threats and that could impact
the operations their assets the entire
Financial wellbeing and probably it has
a it has an exposure to shut shops right
and in this particular domain insurance
can really play a very very pivotal role
in safeguarding their interest right
it's a very critical tool because
ultimately you are transferring the risk
to an insurance company which is going
to help you at the time of any natural
disaster or any Calamity or anything
which comes to in terms of financial you
know uptake that is point number one uh
if I give you some classical examples
what what do we I see when I talk about
insurances uh see one the very classical
uh you know product we call it the
property insurance which products which
protects the you know buyer from
physical assets their buildings their
equipments their plant and machineries
for against Natural Disasters uh theft
fire or any such incident coming their
way they can be safeguarded then they
have a business Interruption going on
where probably if you are you know
failing to deliver your promises to your
end buyer and you have a business uh
Interruption cover taken then business
Interruption cover can help you in
compensating that loss that you could
have incurred there that is something
which is again important then again the
labor Ministry asked to cover their
workers as well so that is how the
insurance policy which workers
compensation policy help their uh the
well-being of the workers working in a
particular unit which is a manufacturing
setup or any other setup for that matter
I'm sure every day in a newspaper we now
keep hearing about uh the Cyber threats
right so cyber is a new threat that
probably now msmes are exposed to cyber
insurance now protects them against the
Cyber threats so there are multiple
product lines for export oriented unit
if I give you a very classical example
uh the goods that they Transit from one
location to the other destination it has
a lot of exposures right and they also
want it to reach at the particular
destination safely so they can also
ensure them in terms of Transit
Insurance exposure that they carry so
there are multiple lines of business
insurances that really helps all these
msmes Andes to safeguard their interest
and post pandemic it has become all the
way more critical and crucial because at
the end of the day it is money which is
there on the stake you know one other
thing and you brought that up over there
right from the point of view of the
employees of these msmes or smmes um
we've seen obviously individuals taking
a lot more cognizance of their own
health especially post the pandemic it's
always been there but nevertheless
pandemic has seen an uptick in that
Focus uh but organizations also for many
reasons are now putting employee
wellbeing at the center of all that they
do whether it is mental health or
physical health uh whether it is
conducting workshops and yoga and you
know we hear so much of the employee
being at the center of that particular
universe and I think the younger people
also right the younger part of the
workforce is quite interested in joining
organizations that appear to be caring
for their well-being and not just your
career or professional growth so in that
context right organizations that offer
group health insurance that's one of the
categories that I want to focus on over
here tell us about the benefits for a
company that takes group health
insurance of as yeah so if you look at
the current situation in the country uh
the cost of medical
hospitalization is increasing every
passing years like like anything if you
look at the percentage growth at is 25
20 20% inflation that we see in a
medical cost uh triggering in the
hospital capitalization it's a huge cost
it's a huge outgo right so now thees
have started realizing the importance of
medical cost which really hits the
employees at the end over the day right
so now smmes have started offering their
employees the health insurance benefit
right the beauty of this plan uh when
you talk about smmes taking a plan
versus individual taking a plan there's
a there's a kind of difference that we
have in the coverages and etc for
example when you buy a corporate
insurance plan or insurance plan you
have an option of covering all the
pre-existing ailments from day one that
is the option that you can explore in it
it also can add a benefit of maternity
for the you know female employees or the
spouses of the employees right so at the
end of the day from the employer side
it's a employee benefit tool right and
it it acts as a wonderful uh you know uh
uh wonderful angle when you talk when
you talk about your probably retaining
your employees or giving them some
benefits because there's a lot of time
when people feel that okay am I really
being Cared by my organization so this
is one of the tool by the HR employee
benefit yes you are being absolutely
more most privileged lot working with us
as an organization it's beautiful Tool
uh the second addition to this I'll say
is a accidental benefit to more than
hospitalization yes it is important
aspect but accidental disabilities or
death of a employee again is a very very
uh you know challenging thing to cover
there's a policy which covers a group
accidental uh feature of a particulares
right and the employees get covered in
it so combination of medical insurance
which is health insurance and accidental
coverage gives a wonderful wonderful
coverage as a benefit tool that is
something which is now picked up very
very rapidly now the other area you
again had dropped that up as when you to
spoke about the different offerings that
we have over here you spoke about cyber
security and that's a huge area right
across businesses across sectors so in
this particular case if a company Falls
victim to a cyber threat or an attack uh
does IC Lombard have any product or
solution for this sort of a scenario
some sort of insurance coverage perhaps
so yes there's a process ibility of uh
you know covering your cyber threat
exposure for example if somebody you
know hacks into a system and gets your
data deleted or hack your data or
something on those R happens it's a big
big uh you know Financial loss for
organizations right so we at ICS lar
certainly has a policy which is uh I can
I can categorize into two formats so one
of the policy covers a retail part of a
you know exposure for example as an
individual if you want to cover my cyber
threats because we have exposed to using
mobile phones internet and so on and so
forth we we are all exposed to it we can
cover our individual interest also as an
organization smmes and msmes if they
want to cover their cyber threat in
their own system yes it is possibility
to cover their own cyber exposures as
well so now the product is available in
the country and the uptake of the
product is phenomenal because at the end
of the day you can Safeguard such risk
which probably people sitting anywhere
in the world can you know just attack
your systems I think nothing like it so
I guess this there's a doability of
covering both the things to gain that
way now I'm coming to one more area and
uh we briefly saw sort of skimmed over
this as well but again details would be
very useful any aspect of a of running a
business involves an element of
logistics right and every year uh
companies incur several losses on
account of non- delivery accidents
misplacements Etc in this context is
there something that you offer msmes who
need to ensure or protect themselves uh
against this sort of
eventuality yeah so I touched upon my
earlier coverages but I'll give you a
more elaborated version now uh see uh
Marine Transit is a part of format which
uh largely covers your risk related to
logistics for example if you are an
export oriented unit and you are you
know transporting your goods from one
destination to the other one port to
other Port yes there's a lot of exposure
that comes because there are multiple
legs that gets changed within the
country or probably in the country you
are sending your goods for right and at
the end of the day it is a it's a you
know sizable exposure because at the end
if the does the goods doesn't reaches
the spot you are liable to uh you know
bear that cost so today the format has
definitely evolved you can cover all the
domestic risk as well probably sending
one uh destination to the other
destination within the country or if you
export unit and you want to export your
goods and sending to other country that
can also be insured it covers your
overturning risk it covers your shortage
non- delivery and a lot of other you
know Associated perils with it's a very
very broad format and a very old format
of insurance so yes Marine Insurance
plays a very very critical role in
safeguarding that indeed you know
something new that IC Lumbard is
credited with is that website the
digital platform that you've created
Forme business risk coverage we are
almost considered to be Pioneers in the
area so tell us a little bit about this
platform that's available to msms yeah
so uh yeah thank you so much for giving
us a compliment yeah we absolutely were
the first ones to launch this uh
platform in ic Lombard wherein we call
this a digital probably where the
customers and the buyers can come to the
website of IC Lombard and can buy the
insurances which probably are needed by
them the couple of insurances which are
easy formatted and easy to buy easy to
understand we kept those as of now for
example uh if you're transiting your
good from one location to other and
immediately you have a need of a policy
you can just simply log into the website
of ICS Lombard and then take the policy
similarly if you have workers you have a
contract being going on and you want uh
workers to be insured in that you can
definitely take a policy from IC Lombard
website so all these small ticket size
policies all the policies which have a
easy understanding by the customers the
customers themselves can go to the
website and buy a policy and it's it's
ease of buying a policy with an
immediate attention to come to the the
other aspect of uh you know the story
ideally you know I should have asked
this question right in the beginning but
better late than never right so what is
IC laas business insurance skater to in
manner of a Target segment who's your
intended audience and who are the
intended beneficiaries of the insurance
business so I think I'll answer it in
two ways first we don't consider it as a
target audience for us these are people
these are customer who are in dire need
of insurances dire need of their risk
which are exposed to be covered and when
we talk about as ICC Lombard as an
institution we have a moral
responsibility to give them the right
coverage right thing so that financially
they are at peace right so for us
there's no target audience there's
nothing no word which exists here yeah
at the end of the day we keep on finding
ways to reach these smes and give them
the solutions that they are looking
ahead because if you ask me today the
awareness of the first topic that you
touched upon the today the problem
statement was awareness right so we
figur out a ways how to reach these
associations these people these smes and
make them aware of the problem problem
statement that they are facing day in
and day out and give them a solution
which is simplistic to understand rather
than a complex solution which we do not
understand in terms of insurance so that
is how we try to create products in the
company which are simplistic can cover
all the exposure that they exposed in a
single format and when policy can serve
the entire purpose of the you know
particular unit that they run so this is
the kind of approach that we keep as
icsa lard but if you were to summarize
um and address a specific question in
the mind of perhaps someone who's part
of or runs and msme what's in it for me
what is the customer really going to
gain from the proposition that uh this
is all about yeah so uh from the
customer point of view if you honestly
ask me uh the understanding of all the
products practically is not possible for
them and I don't expect the customers to
really want to spend time in it because
at the end of the day their basic core
job is something else in non-insurance
right so as an insurance the ultimate
thing that we try to uh really take the
journey ahead is giving them a
simplistic Insurance comprehensive
policy to for the customer they get one
comprehensive policy which largely
insures them in various format for
example if your exposure is related to
fire if your exposure is related to
workers if your exposure is related to
liabilities or Marine so one format
really helps them in getting all those
exposures covered in a simplistic way
right that is what we really look ahead
when we talk about what is there in the
customer for the customer it is a
comprehensive package probably which
helps them in getting fully satisfied uh
fully at Sol is because at the end of
the day they should not put brains they
should not put energy and time in
something which is not their core domain
it is an insurance company domain and a
responsibility of an insurance company
to help them and speaking of help right
helping customers uh that we have this's
is other aspect of things you know I'm
just we just at the time of recording
with you we're just hosting the secret
centa sort of Celebration and one has to
buy gifts and I realize for me it's the
ease with which I can buy a gift so
that's the platform or portal that I'm
going to go to where is the most conven
venient option available to me nearest
and within the time that I need these
items to be delivered to my office so
everybody's gifting is covered um and
that ease of uh conducting or doing
transactions is what I think every one
of us irrespective of what task it is is
looking forward to uh you've told us
about the digital platform but uh is it
really that simple can you know someone
for example just ensure themselves while
chomping into a sandwich or a piece of
cake so certainly when we design this uh
portal which is. lbar.com
the only thing that we had in mind was
keeping the customer first and see how
convenient it can be for a Layman to buy
a policy right so whatever whatever
clicks that we have kept is keeping in
mind if I don't understand Insurance can
I still buy a policy from IC Lombard's
portal that was a premise when we
started launching this thing and that
was a whole discussion that we got
originated and today I'll say yes
certainly we've got a bit success there
because at the end of the day we kept
customer first before everything else in
three clicks you can buy a policy it is
that that ease and convenience that we
have tried to build from our side and
that that is a journey that we will
continue as an Endeavor to take ahead
also one last question right um at the
time of recording this podcast we
looking at 2024 with new eyes right any
personal bucket list of things to do I
like to ask all my guests something
personal about themselves anything
things that you've decided you want to
do in the year 2024 bunge jumping scuba
diving learning to play a guitar no I
think uh yeah so I'm a I'm a marathon
runner right and that is how uh it keeps
me going right so we have a Mumbai
marathon coming very very near so I'm
looking forward for that barathon that
is what something it's immediately in
the card for me on the on the personal
front and nice nice to have a health
kind of an angle thrown in over here
because I'm sure part of running a
marathon is also making sure that you're
fit you eat right you work out every day
sleep well all of that is part of the
territory and here's wishing you the
very best in the upcoming marathon F and
thank you for joining us on I Cafe thank
you so much it's a wonderful pleasure to
speak with all of you thanks wonderful
thanks a lot